大家好, 在这个视频中, 我们将结束我们对cool的概述
Hello again. In this video we're gonna wrap up our overview of cool with one more
写一个很酷的程序的例子, 最后一个例子, 让我们看一个程序
example of writing a cool program. For our final example, let's look at a program
这实际上是在操纵一些有趣的数据结构, 我们从这里开始
that actually manipulates some interesting data structure. So we'll begin here by
打开一个文件, 让我们这次调用我们的程序列表。
opening up a file. And let's call our program list dot CL this time. And as
通常, 我将开始编写我们的主要例程, 以及我们的主要方法。
usual, I will begin by writing our main routine, and our main method. And once
让我们让它从输入输出中继承, 这样我们就可以在这里做输入/输出例程了。
again let's, let's make this inherit from I/O so we can do the I/O routines here.
让我们从一些简单的事情开始, 就像往常一样, 让我们
And let's just begin with something very simple, as always. Let's just have
这是一种打印出“Hello World”的东西, 但用了一种不同寻常的方式。
something that prints out quot;Hello Worldquot; but in a little bit of an unusual way.
让我们, 我们最后会写一个列表, 一个列表抽象, 让我们先
Let's, we're going to end up writing a list, a list abstraction. And let's first
用手工构建一个列表, 或者至少手工构建一个列表的元素, 然后
build a list by hand, or at least build the elements of a list by hand, and then
我们将构建列表抽象并将它们放入一个列表中, 让我们
we'll actually build the list abstraction and put them in a list. So, let's have
一些字符串, 我们会有我们的字符串hello, 这也说明了
some strings. So we will have our string hello, and this will also illustrate how
你同时做多个LET绑定, 我不应该说
you do multiple LET bindings simultaneously. I shouldn't say
同时, 如何做多个让绑定在一个LET表达式中, 所以你可以
simultaneously. How you do multiple LET bindings in one LET expression. So you do
通过列出它们, 注意到它使用逗号作为分隔符
them by just listing them, and notice that this uses commas as a separator rather
比分号作为终止符, 所以这个左绑定将定义为3
than semicolons as a terminator. So this left binding is going to define three
名字, 你好, 世界, 和新线, 所有这些都是字符串, 然后我们要
names. Hello, world, and new line, all of which are strings. And then We're going to
现在把它们打印在屏幕上, 所以我们想要做的是
now print these out on the screen, so we are going to want to be able to do out
字符串, 由于main继承自self, 我们可以在没有对象的情况下做到这一点,
string, and since main inherits from self, we can do that without an object there,
因为它只是, 再次发送到self对象, 我们想要连接
because it just, again, dispatches to the self object. And we want to concatenate
这些字符串以正确的顺序排列, 所以我们要做hello点, 因为hello是
these strings together in the right order. So we'll do hello dot, and since hello is
一个字符串, 它可以连接到世界, 而世界是一个字符串, 所以它可以是
a string, it can be concatenated to world, and world is a string, so it can be
连接到newline, 这应该可以完成这项工作, 就像可能一样
concatenated to newline And that should do the job. And just like probably one more
关于这个的东西, 这些铅绑定在这里, 如果它,
thing about this lead this, these lead bindings here. This notice if it, the
逗号, 逗号是这里的分隔符, 意思是它不会在最后一个之后出现
comma is, the comma is the separator here, meaning it doesn't come after the last one
在列表中, 所以它只是把它分成了列表, 所以它不是一个终结者。
on the list. So it just separates that into the list, so it's not a terminator.
现在我们可以关闭主程序了, 关闭我们的类定义。
And now we can close up our main procedure. Close up our class definition.
保存它, 现在看看它是否编译。哦, 太棒了！第一次尝试。我们运行它, 它
Save it and now see if it compiles. Oh amazing! First try. And we run it, and it
像预期的那样打印hello world, 现在, 让我们, 而不是引入这三个
prints hello world, as expected. So now, let's, instead of introducing the three
将字符串分开, 然后将它们连接在一起, 让我们写一个抽象
strings separately, and then concatenating them together, let's write an abstraction
我们可以建立一个字符串列表, 然后这个抽象就会有一个函数
where we can build a list of strings. And then that abstraction will have a function
在它里面做连接, 好了, 我们会有一个
within it to do the, to do the concatenation. Alright, so we'll have a
类叫做list, 我想, 每个列表都需要有两个组件, 所以
class called list. And, every list needs to, I think, to have two components. So
首先, 它会有列表中的项, 它会是一个字符串。
first, it's gonna have the item that's in the list, and that'll be a string. And
然后当你有一个指向下一个指针, 到列表末尾的指针, 到
then when you have a pointer to the next, to the, to the tail of the list, to the
列表的其余部分, 所以我有一个下一个字段, 点或者是另一个列表, 是
rest of the list. And so I have a next, field that, points or is another list, is
另一个字符串列表, 现在我们需要一些方法来, 为了
another list of strings. Now we need a couple of methods in order to, in order to
使用这个列表。我们需要能够以某种方式初始化一个列表。
use this list. We'll need to be able to initialize a list in some way. So the
初始化函数将获取一个项目, 以及列表的其余部分, 下一部分
initialization function will take an item and, the rest of the list, the next part
在这个列表中, 它会做什么呢？它需要设置
of the list. And, what is it going to do? Well it's gonna need to set the fields of
这个对象, 所以这个必须作为一系列赋值语句来完成
the object, And so this one has to be done as a series of assignment statements. So
我们需要一个语句块我们把这个项目设为I的参数, 我们会
we'll need a statement block and we will set the item to be the I argument. We'll
设置下一个, 属性为N个参数, 现在, 我们想要, 这个
set the next, attribute to be the N argument. And now, we actually want, this
这里的初始化对象, 这个, 这个方法, 返回对象本身。
initialized object here, this, this method here, to return the object itself. So
这样就可以方便地将电话连接到听不清, 所以
that, and that'll be convenient for chained together calls to [inaudible]. So
我们会让它返回self, 它会返回self对象, 这就是结束
we'll have it return self. It'll return the self object. And that's the end of out
语句块, 然后这就是我们方法的结束, 我犯了一个错误
statement block. And then that is the end of our method. And, I made a mistake up
这里, 我们要声明一个编织的返回类型, 它会返回什么
here. We've gotta declare the return type of a knit. And what it's going to return
当然, 它返回一个类型列表的对象, 我需要列出一个列表声明
of course, it returns a, a object of type list. I'll need to put a list declaration
好了, 这就解决了, 编织的问题, 现在我们可以用这个来构建,
there. Alright, so that takes care of, of a knit . And now we can use this to build,
在下面建立一个列表, 那么我们应该怎么做呢？让我们有一个新的变量
build a list down here. So what should we do? Let's actually have a new variable
我们将在这里介绍, 这一系列的铅绑定。
called list. That we'll introduce here in this lead, this series of lead bindings.
让我们从这三个对象中建立一个列表, 我们会说, 我们会有一个
And let's just build a list out of these three objects. So we'll say, we'll have a
新的列表, 然后我们将初始化以包含字符串hello, 以及。
new list, and then we'll initialize to contain the string hello. And. What should
列表的其余部分是？这应该是另一个列表, 它被初始化为
the, rest of the list be? Well that should be another list, which is initialized to
字符串是世界, 而列表文件中应该包含的是另一个
have the string the world. And what should be inside of that list file, is another
新的列表对象, 我们将初始化为新的行, 现在我们要做什么
new list object, which we'll initialize to have new line. And now what do we put
这里, 这里有个小问题, 不是吗？我们需要放一个
here, actually there's a little bit of problem here isn't there? We need to put a
这里是list对象, 但是我们不想分配一个新的列表对象, 我们想要
list object here. But we don't want to allocate a, a new list object, we want
这就相当于一个空指针, 没有名字
that to be really the equivalent of a, of a null pointer. And there's no name for
实际上, 在Cool中, 你不能写空指针的名字, 它是
that in Cool actually, you can't write down the name of a null pointer. It's
被称为void, 没有, 没有, 没有特殊的符号, 所以我们会
called void in Cool. There's no, there's no, no special symbol for that. So we'll
必须创建一个未初始化的变量, 这也将是,
have to create a variable that is just not initialized. And that will be, as well,
类型列表的未初始化变量实际上是空的, 它将是一个空指针。
uninitialized variable of type list will, in fact be void. It'll be a null pointer.
我们称它为nil, 它是一个类型化列表, 没有初始化器, 所以nil
So let's call that nil. And it'll be a typed list, and no initializer. And so nil
这里会指向空的点, 然后我们可以用nil来表示
there will point to nothing or the, the void point. And then we can use nil to
在这里结束我们的列表, 然后我们必须关闭所有的params
terminate our list here. And then we have to close off all the params for all the
在这里嵌套, 我想就是这样, 这就是我们的列表, 好的, 我们有
nesting here. And I think that's it. And so that will be our list. Okay, so we have
这是三个字符串的列表, 现在我们要做的就是把它打印出来。
a list of three strings. And now what we want to do with that is to print it out.
所以我们想要做的是把一个列表从列表中去掉, 然后
And so what we would like to do is to have a list fall off the list, and then a
这个函数会把这个列表拉平我们把它打印出来, 这就是
function that's gonna flatten that list and we'll just print it. So that is the
主程序应该做什么, 现在, 你必须把它写下来
what the, what the main program should do. And now. You have to write the flatten
函数, 所以平展没有参数, 它会返回一个字符串, 它是
function. So flatten takes no arguments. And it's going to return a string. It's
返回一个单弦, 平坦是一个很简单的函数,
going to return a single string. And flatten is a pretty simple function. U h,
我们要做的是, 实际上有两种情况, 一种是如果我们在
what do we have to do. Well. There's really two cases. One is if we're at the
弦的末端, 另一个是如果我们还没有在弦的末端, 那么
end of the string, and the other is if we're not yet at the end of the string. So
我们来测试一下, 那么我们怎么知道我们是不是在弦的末端呢？好吧, 如果
let's, test for that. So how do we know if we're at the end of the string? Well, if
下一个指针是空的, 然后在字符串中没有, 没有更多的东西。
the next pointer is, is void, then there is no, nothing more in the string. And
实际上这是一个很特殊的测试, 它被称为isvoid, 函数,
there actually is a special test for that in Cool. It's called the isvoid, function,
它是这样写的, 如果isvoid, 下一个, 好的, 下一场。
and it's written like this. So if isvoid, of next, okay? So [inaudible] next field.
所以如果下一个域是空的, 那么我们要返回什么呢？保持, 然后
So if the next field is void, then what are we going to return? Keeps. Well then
这里的结果是, item, 不管最后一个元素中的项是什么
the result here is just, the item, whatever the item was in this last element
在列表中, 或者我们想要做的, 否则, 我们想要
of the list. And otherwise What we want to do, Well, otherwise, we want to take the
我们想要连接到它, 这是把剩下的部分拉平的结果
item and we want to concatenate onto it, the result of flattening the rest of the
这是我们的平坦方法, 让我们看看它是否有效, 让我们来编译
list. And that is our flattened method. So let's see if that works. So let's compile
这里有一些语法错误, 让我们回过头来看看是什么
this. And we got a couple of syntax errors here. So let's go back and see what's
继续, 我们这里有一个语法错误, 在最后, 平坦的方法。
going on. So we have a syntax error here, at the end of the, the flatten method. And
我们看到, 我们省略了听不清来关闭一个条件, 所以有条件的
we see that we left out the [inaudible] to close a conditional. So a conditional has
以听不清的方式结束, 好的, 让我们看看它是否有效
to be ended with, with [inaudible]. Alright, and let's see if that's working
现在, 我们仍然有一个语法错误, 在第29行, 这里的错误是我们
now. And we still have a syntax error, at line 29. And the mistake here is that we
忘记声明这个变量的类型, 它是一个列表, 然后
forgot to declare the type of this variable, which is a list. And then it
把它初始化为这个我们写出来的大表达式, 让我
gets initialized to this to this big expression that we wrote out. Lemme just
这里的缩进稍微好一点, 注意, 实际上是
do the indentation a little more nicely here. And notice, something actually is
值得一提的是, 这个定义, 这个变量的定义
worth mentioning here that this definition here, this definition of the variable
列表。依赖于前面的变量的定义, 所以, 每一个
list. Depends on the definition of the previous variables in the let. So, each of
所以当一个let绑定被设定时, 这个被绑定的变量的名字实际上是
so when a let binding is made the name of the variable that's bound is actually
在随后的let表达式中可用, 因此在本例中, 这个变量列表
available in subsequent let expressions. So in this case this variable list makes
使用所有的hello, world, 和newline, 我们之前定义的是相同的
use of all of hello, world, and newline, Which we're defining earlier in the same
让我们把它保存起来, 然后过来编译它, 我们看到了
lead constr uct. Let's save this, and come over here and compile it. And we see we
代码中又出现了一个错误, 所以, 我们来到这里, 我们看到我们犯了一个错误
got another bug in the code. So, we come up here. We see we I've made a mistake
这里, 我用了函数符号来表示下一个是平的
here. I've used functional notation here calling flattened of next and what I
实际上, 想要做的就是将方法压缩到下一种方法, 这就是
actually wanted to do was to dispatch to next on the method flattened. So, that
应该是这样写的, 好吧, 可能现在已经接近了, 我们来看看
should be written like that. All right, Probably getting close now. Let's see if
它还能工作, 它编译, 现在让我们看看它是否运行, 确实如此,
it works yet. Well it compiles and now let's see if it runs. And indeed it does,
打印出来, hello world, 就像我们期望的那样, 现在让我们回到我们的程序
Prints out, hello world, Just as we expected. Now let's go back to our program
让我们用一种方法来概括这个列表的抽象, 假设我们可以有一个
and let's generalize this list abstraction in one way. Let's say that we can have an
任意的对象列表, 而不仅仅是字符串, 这就要求我们
arbitrary list of objects, not just strings. And that will require us to
改变一些东西, 这样它就可以用一个对象来初始化了。
change a few things so it can be initialized now with an object. And now
当需要将这个列表拉平时我们想要减少一个字符串, 我们想要
when it comes time to flatten this list we want to reduce a string. We want to
现在产生一个打印表示, 但不是列表中的所有内容, 都是
present produce a print representation. But not everything in the, in the list, is
必然是一个字符串, 我们需要一种方法来遍历列表, 做不同的事情,
necessarily a string. And we need a way to traverse the list and do different things,
对于不同类型的事物, 不同类型的事物
for different kinds of things that might be in the list for different types of
可能出现在列表中的东西, 所以这是一个很酷的类型
things that might be in the list. And so there's a constructing cool for the type
一个对象的, 和, 在运行时, 这个被称为, 案例结构, 所以,
of, and, of an object, at run time and this is called, the case construct. So,
让我先介绍一个let表达式, 我们会让字符串
let me first introduce a let expression here, we'll let the string that we're
构造, 它是字符串类型的, 它会被初始化为
gonna construct, Which is of type string. And that's going to be initialized to
现在, 它将会是一个案例, 我们要怎么做呢？
something, and now, it's going to be a case. And what do we put a case on? Well,
它将取决于项目的类型, 所以列表中的项目可以
it's going to depend on the kind of thing the item is. So the item in the list could
它可以是不同类型的类型我们想要做一个不同的操作
be, it could be different kinds of types and we want to do a different operation
取决于具体项目是什么, 所以案例项目和关键字是
depending on what item actually is. So the case item and then the key word is of, and
现在我们有了不同的案例表达的不同分支,
now we have different branches of the case expression for different kinds of things,
这可能在列表中, 假设这是一个听不清, 好的, 那么
that could be in the list. So let's say that if it's an [inaudible]. Okay, so what
这就是说, 如果这个项是整数, 那么我们要重命名它
this does, is this says that if the item is an INT, then we're going to rename it
对于I, 我们要把I绑定到那个整数然后我们可以做一些事情
to I, we're going to bind I to that integer and then we can do something with
我。我们要怎么处理呢？好吧, 我们可能想要把它转换成
I. And what would we want to do with I? Well, we'd probably want to convert it to
一个字符串, 所以我们要把I变成"I"如果事实上, 这个项目碰巧是
a string. So we'll do I to A quot;Iquot; And what if in fact. That item happened to be of
类型字符串。列表中的项目必须是字符串类型的, 那么我们就可以
type string. The items in the list have to be of type string. Well, then we can just
使用这个项目本身, 作为字符串表示, 我们可以这样做
use the item itself, as the string representation. And we can do this for
其他类型的类型, 如果我们的系统中有其他类型的类型, 我们可以
other kinds of types. If we had other kinds of types in our system, we could
继续列出其他的, 案例, 以及如何将它们转换为字符串
continue to list out other, cases here, and how to convert them into a string
表示, 但我们这里有一个默认的情况, 我们会说如果它是任意的
representation. But let's just have a default case here. We'll say if it's any
另一种类型, 也就是, 有分支, 有分支
other kind of type, which would, which would be covered by having, a branch
如果它是, 类型对象, 我们称它为O, 那么我们就应该
saying that if it's, of, type object, we'll call it O, then we should just
中止, 所以我们应该调用中止函数然后退出, 这是我们的
abort. And so we should just call the abort function and quit. And that's our
案例, 它需要用一个关闭的关键字esag来结束, 同样的
case. It needs to be terminated with a closing keyword called esag, Again the
相反的, 现在我们可以用我们在我们的基础上构建的
reverse of, of case. And now we can use that [inaudible] we constructed in our
这里的函数很小, 如果下一个字段是空的那么我们就会返回
little function here. So if, if the next field is void then we're just gonna return
字符串, 否则我们会返回这个字符串与
the string. Otherwise we're gonna return this string incatenated with the
把剩下的部分都拉平了, 凯, 现在我们有几件事
flattening out of the rest of the list. Kay. Now there's a couple of things we
必须要修正, 我们在这里使用I到一个方法, 这意味着列表需要
have to fix up. We used the I to A method here, which means that list needs to
从A转到I, 这里还有一个问题, 我明白了。
inherit. From the, conversion class A to I. And there's another issue here, I see.
这就在这里, 如果你注意到, 案例陈述需要
And that's right here. So, if you notice The, the. The case statement needs to
产生一个弦, 好的, 结果是中止剂量不返回一个弦, 中止
produce a string. Okay, and it turns out that abort dose not return a string, abort
实际上终止了这个程序, 但是它的类型是它返回一个对象, 所以
actually terminates the program, but it's type is that it returns an object. And so
这里我们要说服类型检查器, 说服, 接受这个,
here we have to convince the type checker, to convince, to accept this, piece of
代码, 我们需要让这个分支在这里输入一个字符串, 我们可以做的是,
code, and we need to get this branch here to type as a string. So what we can do,
这很难看, 但这是一种方法, 我们把它放在一个block中
and this is ugly, but it's the way to do it, is we put it in a block, in a
语句块, 我们先调用中止, 然后得到一个增益, 它会终止
statement block. We call abort first, and a gain, that will just terminate the
程序, 现在我们可以在它之后加上任何字符串表达式, 然后
program. And now we can put any string expression we want after that, and that'll
是, 它会给整个block提供一个类型字符串, 所以我们可以放空
be the, that'll give a type string to the entire block. So we can just put the empty
例如, 这里的字符串, 必须用分号终止, 因为这个
string here, for example, and that has to be terminated with a semicolon, since this
这不是块, 我们可以用花括号来结束, 好了, 这就是
isn't a block. And we can close, that, with a curly brace. Okay? So this is just
我们必须要做的事情, 让类型检查器高兴, 这可能就是一切
something we have to do, to make the type checker happy. And that may be everything
我们需要这样做, 让我们试着编译这个, 我们必须包括转移
we needed to do. So let's try compiling this. And we have to include the diversion
我们有一个语法错误, 到目前为止, 那是因为我们忘记了
library. And we have one syntax error. So far. And that's because we forgot to put
分号终止符, 在每一个, 每一个, 每一个, 变量
the, semicolon terminator on, on each of our, each of the, each of the, variables
我们在Let中引入的, 好了, 保存一下, 我们再试一次。
that we were introducing in the let. Okay, got to save that. Let's try this again.
哦, 我并没有真正解决语法错误, 那是因为我放了
And, oops, I didn't actually manage to fix the syntax error. And that's because I put
在错误的地方用分号, 实际上, 我忘了, 变量是
the semicolon in the wrong place. Actually, I, I forgot. Variables that are
借出的债券是用逗号隔开的, 但是, 这个案例的分支
bond in a lent are separated by, by commas. But, the branches of the case have
被分号终止, 所以, 我之前说的是不正确的
to be terminated by semicolons. So, what I said before was incorrect about using
分号来终止借出的绑定, 这只是我们需要的分支
semicolons to terminate lent bindings. It's just in case branches where we need
在这个例子中, 好的, 不管怎样, 回到这个问题我们来看看
it, In this example. Alright, anyway coming back to this let's see if it
编译, 它会。现在让我们运行它, 它起作用了, 当然我们没有
compiles. And it does. And now let's run it, And it works. Now of course we haven't
实际上利用了在列表中有不同类型的对象的能力
actually exploited the ability to have different types of objects in the list. So
让我们来做一下, 让我们在这里添加一个整数, 输入ints, 让我们, 给它a
let's, let's do that. Let's add an integer in here. Type ints and let's, give it a
第42题, 我们可以把它插入到这里, 现在我们可以把任何对象, 变成一个编织
number 42. And we can insert it in here. And now we can pass any object, to a knit
在第一个位置, 所以我们把42放在这里, 当我们编译的时候
in the first position. So we'll just put in 42 right there. And when we compile and
运行这个, 它只打印hello world 42, 如果我们, 如果一切都像预期的那样
run this it just print hello world 42. If we, if everything goes as expected, And it
这就结束了我们的小旅行, 听不清, 有一些特点
does, And that concludes our little tour of [inaudible]. There are a few features
我们在这些例子中没有展示过, 但是你们可以看一下例子
that we haven't shown in these examples, but you can look in the examples
目录, 用于更多的程序-更多的专业信息将会显示所有的内容
directory, for lots more programs - many more pro grams that will show you all the
不同的语言和细节以及其他语言的细节, 以及
different ins and outs and details of the other language features as well as the
我们已经讲过了。
ones we've covered here.